Folks, it's the first week of January and, I'm here with Paula King and we're gonna give you a quick walkthrough of the community center as it's under construction.
So right now you're looking at the front entrance
to the building.
As you can see, the the grade
is,
a lot lower than it will be. The black line is right about what the final grade for the building is.
So there'll be a circular entrance
to the front of the building, so you'll be able to drive right up,
and that will be the main entrance to the building.
So let's go inside
and take a look at what's inside.
>> Here's our happy building official, Mitch. Hello. Hey, Paula King. Here's a video for the residents of Andover. We're just doing a walk through. So Yeah. We're looking at our inspector now. With plumbman. Thank you. Thank you.
>> That's a politician.
Okay.
So we're now standing in the the main entrance vestibule to the building. So you'll come in here. There'll be a coat rack on the side,
and you'll open a second door,
and you'll be in a main hallway to the building.
Okay. So the first room here
will be the main office for the person that will be managing the building. It's got a lot of natural light.
It gets to look out on the hallway.
It's right next to the kitchen,
and the cameras will come to this room.
So that person will be able to monitor everybody in the room.
Right next to this room is the kitchen.
So
we're now standing in kitchen. The kitchen will have a large serving window out to the main part of the building.
There's gonna be multiple sinks,
commercial cooktop behind you,
coffee maker, large fridge,
and ice maker, and all the usual things you're gonna find in a kitchen.
K.
Moving along, this building will be storage.
This will be a locked room.
It will contain
the
the mop sink for the custodian,
and it will also contain
storage both for chairs and tables
as well as food storage,
eventually
for,
meals on wheels programming.
And
then this is a second
small office slash conference room.
This will have a locking door.
This will be set up so that it can
do a variety
of things.
One of them will be could be used as an exam room. It can be used as a counseling room.
It can be used as a general purpose
small meeting room. So it's got a lot of functions,
and it's still accessible to the main part of the building.
And right next door are two bathrooms.
So they're both fairly small, but both bathrooms are ADA accessible.
And this bathroom will have a walk in shower.
And part of that is so that we're able to use this building as our emergency shelter in the future because we'll have the ability to cook, the ability to shower, the ability to house a lot of people in an emergency.
Okay. And now we move on to the largest room
of the Main Floor.
If you look, this room has a
vaulted ceiling so it feels nice and big and open
And it is designed
for a variety of purposes.
It can work as a large meeting room,
and it can also work as
a dining room area.
Pretty much any event can be held in this space.
And this room has its own two exits.
This
have
then little of
door.
Of
This space will also have its own bit
closet for a coats and things of that nature.
And then it's also being set up to take a large
projection TV,
so this can be a movie room
and,
can also function for conferences and meetings.
Pretty good.
So,
eventually, this will have there'll be blinds in all the windows
so we can bring the light level down very low for movie nights or what. Light by stop. Whatever. So if we need to see do a good job of seeing what's on the projection screen.
And
then the last room in here is
a smaller multipurpose
room.
This room is designed to be the
kind of like a lounge slash small meeting slash arts and crafts room. So, again, it would be very multipurpose.
It will also have the ability to have a large TV in it,
and we'll probably use the couch from the community room in here and set this up as a nice warm inviting. Alright, folks. So we're now standing on the side and looking at the rear
of the community center. This is the lower level. Level.
There
will be quite a bit of fill brought in to bring the grade up by the building.
So, it won't look like this when it's done, but the basement will be fully walk out, and there will be direct access and
a
sidewalk that comes from the lower
the parking lot between the fire department and the town hall.
Now we're gonna walk into the,
lower level of the building.
That's
>> actually not too bad. It's pretty in on screen, it's not too bad.
That's about You're gonna be my spotlight? That's why have a point. Point here.
>> Okay.
So we're now in the lower level of the community center.
The lower level was designed to be one large meeting space.
The majority of the building is open with just two lolly columns.
And this will be fully drywalled,
fully insulated,
fully heated, and cooled.
So it will be one large open space.
And
we're still not
haven't made final decisions on what usage
will be down here,
but this is envisioned to be a small gym space,
kind of an open area
for yoga or tai chi or things of that nature.
It will probably also be available for people for
events and parties.
And then we're talking about possibly putting down a pool table or something like that, for recreation
if people want to hang out here.
This will also have two storage rooms which you can see in the back. That's the primary storage room.
There'll also be a little storage
back in the mechanical room, but not a lot.
But this main part will not be for storage.
It will be for assembly and for use.
We're also
plumbed in for two bathrooms in the basement
right here and right here. These bathrooms will also be, you know, fully ADA compliant.
So they'll be fully usable, but we're not installing the bathrooms at this time just because we don't have the budget to do it.
And we also have the plumbing installed
right out here for a water cooler.
So because there's no kitchen down here,
people are working out or whatever, they'll at least have a a place to get water and bottle fillers.
Correct.
And then this room right here
will be predominantly
the mechanical
room.
As you can still you can see that's still being plumbed in. The electrical will be right there, and this is the primary plumbing
for the building.
And that's basically what you have for a community center.